Avni Patel

(518) 605-2995 | Albany, New York | avni0000patel@gmail.com | https://github.com/avni0000patel@gmail.com | https://avni0000patel.github.io/React-Portfolio/

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Developer with knowledge in information technology, software development cycle, finance, mathematics, statistics, and research. Experience with front-end and back-end frameworks designing, developing, and implementing scalable websites, applications, and solutions using a range of technologies and programming languages. Developed 20+ websites from scratch using technologies including Git, JavaScript, Node, SQL, MongoDB, React, and MERN Stack.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Technologies: Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Bootstrap, The DOM, Rest APIs, jQuery, JSON, AJAX, Node.js, ES6, Object-Oriented Programming, Express.js, MySQL, MVC Paradigm, Sequelize, Testing, Scrum, and Agile Software Development, NoSQL, MongoDB, React, MERN Stack, State, TypeScript, fundamentals in Computer Science, MATLAB, Bus Financial Forecasting, Fixed Income, Derivatives, CFA, Calculus II, Calculus III, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations, and Probability for Statistics.

EDUCATION

University of Pennsylvania

Philadelphia, PA

Certificate

• An intensive program focused on gaining skills in full-stack web development.

Siena College Loudonville, NY

Bachelor of Science in Finance, Minor in Mathematics (GPA: 3.84)

• A degree primarily focused on a CFA track and gaining analytical skills, data analytics skills, and valuation skills.

PROJECTS

AutismFY | https://github.com/avni0000patel/AutismFY | https://hidden-beach-19071.herokuapp.com/

- Led the front-end and back-end framework and collaborated with a team of 4 people to create an application for Autistic parents and caregivers.
- Built using MERN Stack technologies with React as the front-end framework, Express.js and Node.js as the server-side framework, and MongoDB as the database.
- Other technologies used include Bootstrap as a CSS framework to set up a mobile-friendly front-end design, Material-UI to import and use different components to create a user interface, GraphQL as a runtime for fulfilling those queries with your existing data, Apollo Client to manage both local and remote data with GraphQL, Redux to direct state and state transformations, Axios to make HTTP requests from the browser, JSON Web Tokens to securely transfer information between parties, UUID as a universally unique identifier to provide a unique identity to any collection of information, and testing libraries including Jest-Dom, React, and User Event.

 $\label{linear_match_me} \textbf{Rig Match Me} \mid \underline{\text{https://github.com/avni0000patel/Rig-Match-Me}} \mid \underline{\text{https://serene-thicket-89290.herokuapp.com/}} \mid \underline{\text{https://serene-thicket-89290.herokuapp.com/}} \mid \underline{\text{https://www.rigmatchme.com/}}$

- Led the back-end framework and collaborated with a team of 3 people to make an application for musicians to set up a new rig easily.
- Constructed using Bootstrap as CSS framework to create a responsive front-end application design, Node.js as a
 back-end JavaScript runtime environment, MySQL as the relational database management system, Dotenv to create
 environment variables in a .env file, Bycrypt to hash and salt passwords securely, Axios to make HTTP requests from
 the browser, Sequelize as a connection to an Object Relational Mapper for better database synchronization, Express.js
 to oversee servers and routes, Express-handlebars to create dynamic webpages that render on the server-side,
 Nodemailer to send and receive emails, and Jest as the testing framework.

Tech Blog | https://github.com/avni0000patel/Tech-Blog | https://boiling-tor-98375.herokuapp.com/

- Developed the front-end and back-end framework of an application for developers to publish a blog post and comment on other developers' blog posts.
- Designed using Bootstrap as CSS framework to create the front-end scheme, Node.js as a back-end framework, MySQL as the database, Dotenv to create environment variables in a .env file, Bycrypt to build a password security platform, Sequelize to easily manage a SQL database, Express.js to manage the server side, and Express-handlebars to render web pages to the client side from data on the server side.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Merrill Lynch Albany, NY

Wealth Management Client Associate

November 2021 - Present

Supply operational support to 20+ financial advisors in a fast-paced environment, assisting in all areas of practice
including administration, business management, professional development, relationship management, and technical
support.

- Lead client's digital experience and drive the firm to embrace online Merrill platforms, create ease of access and integration to Merrill systems, and protect the privacy and security of clients.
- Engage clients in eDelivery to work toward an online delivery goal of 85% for statements, prospectus, service notices, tax reporting statements, and trade confirms and enroll clients in MyMerrill and inquire further if clients did not access MyMerrill within the past 90 days if enrolled.
- Process all client requests including asset allocation changes, account transfers, fund transfers, retirement account
 distributions/contributions, beneficiary designations, performance and research reports, cost-basis issues, and all
 account maintenance.

Wyndham Hotels and Resorts

Albany, NY

Administrative Assistant

June 2014 - Present

- Manage hotel operations and finances to deliver a successful hospitality business focused on delivering exceptional service and increasing productivity, efficiency, and profitability.
- Operate and offer technical support for SynXis cloud-based property management system to arrange an integrated solution to the hotel website allowing control of the design and layout.
- Work with the franchise service manager to enhance SynXis cloud-based system by 45% improving operating systems.
- Analyze star reports to increase occupancy, average daily rate, and revenue per room by an index of over 100%.

Siena College Loudonville, NY

Management Tutor

September 2020 - May 2021

 Taught struggling college students concepts of Operations Management and the skills emphasized in the course included applying analytical techniques to decision-making, independent demand inventory models, project management, and statistical process control.

Center for Undergraduate Research and Creative Activity (CURCA) Intern

May 2020 - September 2020

- Conducted extensive research and gathered statistics from 18 countries in Latin America and the Caribbean to address the inequalities people face, predominantly based on gender, racial, socioeconomic, and generational differences.
- Addressed factors that affect college student funding including the extent to which students will take loans, predominantly based on demographic, socioeconomic, and perceptual factors.
- Attended Global Conference on Business and Finance (GCBF), presented my publication and research to professors
 across the country and was awarded CURCA Student of the Week for the distinctive research collected and presented
 to academics.

South Colonie Central School District

Albany, NY

Special Education Teaching Assistant

July 2017 - August 2019

- Adapted activities, content, methods, and instructions to the individual needs and abilities of students with different physical and learning disabilities ages 5-21 to give them opportunities for success and growth.
- Lowered emotional outbursts and disciplinary incidents by 95% in students by integrating healthy strategies to combat behavioral issues.